SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Front End Web UI with Full Stack Experience

Versatile and thorough Web applications developer skilled at producing great user interfaces and dashboards for end users. Experienced at full stack development too. Balances systems-thinking with attention-to-detail to solve whole-product challenges with a high level of quality. Continually collaborates with others to improve UX and demystify complexity in the design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, ExtJS, ReactJS, VueJS, Highcharts.
- Tools: REST APIs, VSC, Git, Bitbucket, vim, Sublime Text 2, Photoshop, Balsamiq, Omnigraffle.
- Methods: OOP, SPA, wikis, user-centered design (UCD), wireframes, card sorting, site maps.

SAMPLE WEB APPS

- <u>ComparingStocks</u>: Tool for generating meaningful performance and allocation data for stock holdings; ReactJS, Alpha Vantage API; https://roderickwoodman.github.io/comparingstocks/.
- <u>TrailProfiler</u>: Charts and edits together GPX trail files and their associated JPG photo files; VueJS, ChartistJS, Bootstrap; https://roderickwoodman.github.io/trailprofiler/.
- <u>BoardGameinator</u>: Boardgame comparison site; ReactJS, Bootstrap, BoardGameGeek.com API; https://roderickwoodman.github.io/boardgameinator/.

EXPERIENCE

ARUBA NETWORKS, Santa Clara, CA

2016 - 2020

1800-person mobile-first networking company owned by Hewlett Packard Enterprise Company.

Senior Applications Engineer - Support Portal for Aruba Central Guest

- Jointly responsible on a team of 6 for a Web front-end dashboard (AngularJS, Bootstrap) and a cloud-hosted backend (Pyth0n, AWS); continuous integration development on a cloud-native product.
- Added troubleshooting features, like a RadSec capture UI, to help the support admins diagnose errors.
- Connected to 3rd party APIs like Twilio and SendGrid.
- Documented and disseminated the broader system architecture by communicating with developers in multiple orgs and then sharing it on the Confluence wiki.

Senior Applications Engineer - Config Sync tool for ClearPass

- Solely responsible for the ClearPass config sync tool that allows network admins to audit and optionally remediate the configurations of 100 clusters at once; the application is a Web front-end dashboard (ExtJS, SASS) and an Aruba-ClearPass-hosted backend (G0, REST APIs).
- Wireframed the UI design based on customer input.
- Created custom, internal APIs to connect the front end to the back end.
- Implemented back-end sorting, filtering, and exporting of audit results.

TRUEPATH WIRELESS, San Jose, CA

2015 - 2016

11-person startup that provided terrestrial, wireless Internet to cruise ships near port.

Senior Software Engineer - Network Management System

- Solely responsible for the Network Management System (NMS) product.
- Coded logs, displays, and reports all of the continuously collected network quality data from dozens of mobile endpoints; includes device-side "agent" code (PHP/bash/cron), Web front-end

- dashboard code (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, HighCharts, Google Maps), and server back-end code (Pth0n, Fl@sk, M0ngoDB, REST).
- Redesigned the dashboard UI to support multiple endpoint types and additional data streams. Gathered requirements from customer and business stakeholders.
- Sped up the pace of NMS improvements by releasing new code every 2-3 weeks.
- Collaborated with FW and network engineers to integrate new, third-party endpoint hardware
- Designed and implemented a compression algorithm that reduced the device-generated network quality stats files to 16% of their original size.

CISCO, San Jose, CA 2005 – 2014

Diagnostic Software Engineer

Catalyst 6000 and Nexus 6K (network switches)

HEWLETT-PACKARD, Cupertino, CA

2001 - 2005

Bring-up Engineer - Hardware & Software

NonStop Servers (fault tolerant compute)

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Engineering Santa Clara University, Santa Clara, CA

Bachelor of Science in Electronic Engineering California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, CA

CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING

MEAN Stack Blackbelt - Coding Dojo, San Jose, CA
Web Design Certificate - UCSC Extension Silicon Valley, Santa Clara, CA

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Photography. Writing. Editing. Deciding what matters most. Being a youth soccer referee.